<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on El Fubu</title>
    <link>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/categories/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on El Fubu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-UK</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 07:37:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/categories/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modifying a Sony Hitbit 10P to use a standard barrel jack power supply</title>
      <link>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/2022-03-13-hitbit10p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 07:37:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/2022-03-13-hitbit10p/</guid>
      <description>Greetings everyone!
A couple of weeks ago I got a Sony HitBit 10p from a mechanical keyboard enthusiast from the University, a great guy :). He know where to leave MSX things. There was a particular issue: There was no power supply. After changing one power supply for a Sony HB-T7 I thought that it would not be much of a problem. And actually it was not!

I found a tutorial in spanish on how to do this with a phone charger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing MSX HB-T7 Power Supply Unit</title>
      <link>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/2019-07-09-changing_t7_power_unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 08:03:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/2019-07-09-changing_t7_power_unit/</guid>
      <description>Hellllooooo everyone!
I&amp;rsquo;m alive, again. Maki asked me to make a blog post about how we changed the MSX HitBit T7 japanese power supply unit (from now on PSU) for a more modern and european one. So, let&amp;rsquo;s do this.
Update (2020-05-29): Victor Muñoz tutorial Victor Muñoz followed this post (plus the discussion we have had on email) and did this mod. He has shared with me a PDF containing the tutorial he has made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony HitBit 55/75P dead VRAM diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/2017-02-25-sony-hitbit-5575p-dead-vram-diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.gamerachan.org/fubu/dijkstra/2017-02-25-sony-hitbit-5575p-dead-vram-diagnosis/</guid>
      <description>Hey!
Recently I bought a broken 75P just for fun (and well, it was cheap :)). It had a video problem which, after reading a couple of msx.org posts (Hit-bit With Broken Graphics and 75P black screen mainly), I believed it was a problem of VRAM as Grauw pointed.
That was a clever way to debug it. Watching how Basic characters are output, you can see which bit is broken in the ASCII chart.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
